<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Square Zero]]></title><description><![CDATA[Silent Observations]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 11:12:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Impending Anarchy]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s a normal night. We’re having fun. The gang and I have zoned out in our balcony. It’s very late into the night, and everything is…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/impending-anarchy/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/impending-anarchy/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s a normal night. We’re having fun. The gang and I have zoned out in our balcony. It’s very late into the night, and everything is alright. Except for the news that broke out a few hours ago about how
“the state has collapsed. We are taking over. Decades of mediocrity are over. Enough being fools. It’s time for you to take control of it yourself. Together, we will re-orient ourselves to serve the grand purpose. Join us, or you will be executed.”
spoke a mad man in a mask after hacking into every piece of tech we all owned. We laughed it off; there was an important party to be had, and this fascinating stunt could be discussed and scoffed at tomorrow.
The power went off a couple of hours ago; it usually comes back in 15. Weird. We’re singing songs and chatting pop culture when the door bell of a house across the street rings for 50 times without a break. ‘Someone can’t hold their pee, jeez’ we crack a joke, but we are spooked. The door bell stops ringing. ‘They must’ve had a generator. This guy must be testing it, bloody drunk’ we laugh hysterically to eclipse the fact that we’re all spooked.
Far far away, someone starts banging their drums really loud. It’s past 3am, what is that noise? It starts sounding more and more like a war drum. It’s periodic, it’s intentional, it’s vehement and it’s incessant. It goes on for a while as we wonder how the person hasn’t been shouted down or stopped otherwise by their neighbors. We hear two people in our street argue now. They have been doing it for at least the past hour, but now it’s loud and dirty. People are getting impatient. Law seems to have been forgotten, and chaos seems to have taken over instead. We hear the siren of a fire truck close by, and the sound of it crashing into a house.
We’re not laughing anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The best Thanksgiving]]></title><description><![CDATA[” What are we doing here? We’re fussing about how long it takes to get to work, and how difficult it is to please our boss, how efficient…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/thanksgiving/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/thanksgiving/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;” What are we doing here? We’re fussing about how long it takes to get to work, and how difficult it is to please our boss, how efficient your workout plan is, how a small hack saves you 20 dollars on a pizza ! Is this what 13 billions of years led to? The price of your freaking pizza? You ranting about others on the internet? Or you bragging how superior your culture is, compared to the rest? We are magnanimously devoting our lives to us. Ourselves. Or our families. Or maybe humanity. Or in extremely rare cases the other beings of the planet. See, we are completely ignoring the powerful gift we’ve been given. We’re the only beings on the planet who can read and understand this blog. Think about it! We have sentience. Conscience. Senses which have been harnessed only by our species. We are actually able to stop, think, decide and take control of our future. We are the supreme beings of the planet. No one better exists, at least in the known universe. But unfortunately, we’ve gotten complacent now, and started taking things for granted. Why sir? All the frivolous decisions we make, the trivial problems we’re surrounded with, have NO impact on the universe. Ever. What’s the purpose of existing if we don’t make a dent in the freaking space? Why not dedicate our unparalleled wisdom and unmatched inquisitiveness to explore the corners of the universe? Why not crack the uncrackable human mind? Why not break the unbreakable code that governs the universe? Why not create a million more and implant the seed for the explosion? Why not get out of that milieu and reach out with the irrepressible zeal we have? Why not live the way it’s meant to be? ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I posted this right after getting home from one of the best evenings of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little background: I volunteered a couple of times handling a food stall as part of a charity during football games at my Master’s school. One of the many perks that had was an invitation to a Thanksgiving party at a professor’s house. I rsvp’d, and took along Aditya and Yuvaraj. We were picked up by an older guy with a car. That was the first time I had gone farther than college in Gainesville. The roads, the neighborhoods, the trees and yards in the evening light will stay fresh in my mind forever. Tree of life vibes. The guy had a nice big home in a neighborhood. I still have a video I had taken while walking to the place from the porch. I used to take a ton of pics and vids back in the day. Anyway, there were some familiar faces there from the volunteer thing. We talked, joked and hung out till dinner. Oh, the dinner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sumptuous food, followed by some heavenly apple pie and other desserts, some Indian, some not. Their hospitality was just too sweet. The lady of the house had that Bengali charm, commanding and strong. I was actually in a house in the United States. I was still dazed. Then we all sat in the living room, and the prof, Mr. K started talking about what he was thankful for; I had no idea what he was saying, I was just too young. Then all of us started sharing what we were thankful for. You know us Indians, we like following the lead, following the pattern et al, right? Everyone was just saying “Yeah, I’m thankful for my parents, friends, family”, whatever. I wasn’t even feeling derisive, but indifferent because all the stories were banal. Then came my turn, and I don’t know what happened. This thought just appeared out of nowhere and got out of my mind through my words. I started saying something like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think I’m thankful for randomness? I guess. Because a year ago, I would not have guessed even a little that I would be here today. Here in the usa, in this house, doing this. It’s completely random and by chance. Yeah, so I think it’s randomness I’m thankful for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t doing this to appear like something I wasn’t, or to appear smarter than thou. The thought and words just came out. And I felt awesome about it after I finished speaking. That was a spark of I wouldn’t say intelligence, but a greater understanding and brilliance. That moment somehow affected me deeply, and I was a different person now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were all bidding goodbye, a man shook my hand, and said “I like your perspective; your thinking, I think it’s great” while smiling. I felt so proud of myself right then, and existential at the same time. Here I was, stranger in a strange land, having no business here, and still living the night and seeing the wonder in it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That led to the words I spit out onto facebook, while in the zone. Granted, this feeling and perspective slowly faded away, but every once in a while, I think about that one night, and it gives me inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spy game - Mercs]]></title><description><![CDATA[We’re a bunch of mercs, hitmen, assassins, whatever you wanna call it. We’re hired for very specific tasks that tip the scales toward our…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/mercs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/mercs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We’re a bunch of mercs, hitmen, assassins, whatever you wanna call it. We’re hired for very specific tasks that tip the scales toward our clientele. Ever since the last war, the puppet masters figured out it was best to lay in the shadows and pull the strings from the shadows. Lately, I’ve been rolling with Nik and Mag. It’s been a couple of years, and we’re tight or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the client wants us to silence a high value target without any noise. Nothing too heavy; we need to infiltrate a giant party, find the right moment our guy slips into his room, and take him out.
We sneak into a giant complex where the party is being hosted. This is an expensive and swanky party. Every VIP from the colony is here. That’s actually great, because our target isn’t who the eye balls are on. The HVT is already in his room. Great. Not so great, there’s cctvs everywhere.
We don balaclavas as we sneak into his floor. The cctv guys have been taken care of, so that got us some time.
We barge into his suite, tell him what was to be said, and take care of the matter. Great view from his suite, I admired out loud before taking the shot. However, as soon as we exit his room the alarms ring. Someone got into the cctv room. Or have we been setup?
We make a dash in different directions. I get to the emergency stairs, get near the basement exit and see a homeless guy smoking crack near a dumpster fire. I hear footsteps and hide next to the elevator. I see 10-15 swat guys getting out of the elevator and proceeding through the same stairs upwards. How is the swat already here? I know I’ve worn the balaclava near cameras, so my outfit is the only giveaway. I barter clothes for some money with the hobo and chuck my clothes in his trash. I get out into the compound and blend with the guests.
Mag and nik made it out too. Sweet! Close call…
.
We’re in the usa. We just got into the house of the guy giving us our next assignment. He’s a complete creep. Has a family, but is ‘housing’ a few more ladies right in the next house. The whole building is his. We’re staying there till the time is right to begin his assignment. Guy is fkin weird.
Maybe this guy has some dirt on some big wig; no way he has the currency to sponsor this escapade otherwise.
“Pretty sure he’ll blow up soon” I mutter.
“I concur” Nik concurs…
.
We’re made. Nik and Mag are awol.
The creepy guy has his cover, and head blown. I creep around the neighborhood as swat is sweeping the area. I hold off until midnight in a ditch; I see a stealth chopper arriving. I dive into a lake and they rope me in. The moon shines bright as I quickly change into a soldiers outfit as they debrief me that this mission was a bust. I’m actually on my way to Mexico. We follow a river along the jungle. I’m rappelled out into a group of 10 soldiers who are about to attack an outpost. They’ve been briefed to expect a specialist joining them but he’s been taken care of, and I’ve taken his place. I speak their language and they’ve no idea who I really am. We’re making our way to the outpost as I switch my night vision on. My Misson is to take care of another HVT who’s visiting the outpost. “Serendipity” was the word the pilot used. I’m gonna take his possessions and live in his mansion till I get the brief on the next mission.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to blog regularly]]></title><description><![CDATA[An unlikely place for advice Ironically, I may be the best person to give you advice on this. I’ve been there, and I’ve done it all. I have…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/how-to-blog-regularly/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/how-to-blog-regularly/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;An unlikely place for advice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, I may be the best person to give you advice on this. I’ve been there, and I’ve done it all. I have slouched and dilly-dallied, I’ve drafted and deleted, I’ve written and stashed. I can show you all the ways you can mess up a perfect flow. I know all the cracks in your plans, and the fallacies in your presumptions. Paradise is a distant dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mind-body-mind: the vicious cycle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lethargy induces mental coma; torpor leads to a writers block/creative rut. This in turn engenders lazy behaviour, and the cycle is as vicious and pernicious to the mind as it is to the body. You’ve gotta stay fit physically to stay in mental shape, and vice versa is equally important.
Slacking off regularly and getting complacent shrouds your vision of the grand plan, and the body follows suit. This is a two way street. You gotta command over both manifestations of your soul. I can’t count enough instances of taking a walk after a long break, and new energy rushing over me. It’s pure magic. Being in motion really does get your brain going. Get up and move your ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;New experiences trigger new ideas&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New experiences might not necessarily give you more content to work with, but they will at least change your perspective and make you think differently. Again, there’s a certain energy that…energizes you with every new experience.
Knowledge and perspective are inseparable, I recently observed. You’re not just data collecting every moment you live. We’re not data storage units. We’re perspective storage units. Every second we perceive, our mind trains itself with this new dataset, and the new memories are accompanied with updated patterns for logic, problem solving, threat identification, feelings, and questions. You can’t just acquire knowledge and stash it in your brain. You get the perspective too.
So, more knowledge-&gt;better perspective, since more is indubitably better to make the correct decision in the future.
What I mean is, you might assume that you have the hottest take on a subject, but five years later you look back on it and…with your wisdom you see how naive and parochial your older self was.
Get out, do new things, read more, consume good content, and experiences. They will shape you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Keep Post-it notes!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s worse than forgetting to complete a task? Forgetting about the task entirely. The key is to be cognizant of all tasks that you’ve left unfinished. It’s great to have a visual reminder always in front of you, so you don’t lose track of them in the long term. I personally struggle with being easily distracted and being myopic. So far, post-it notes have aided greatly in keeping me on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;It’s okay to not finish a blog in one go&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is not a fever trip. You don’t have to pour all your emotion and effort into a single run and push the product out. You’re not doing this for money; so there’s no need to rush. You’ve got to restrain the urge to finish prematurely and mark the activity as done. The only lasting takeaway you will then have on retrospection is the regret that you rushed it. It’s not worth it. It is way better to be late than be crude. The other plus of taking it slow is, now you’re able to draft multiple pieces and pick one up based on how you’re feeling that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This is not just about blogging&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One common theme throughout the piece has been how all of this can be applied not just to blogging, but lifestyle in general. Being able to plan, track and complete multiple large tasks is the stuff of legends. Applying that to blogging should be a great way to let discipline seep into other stuff you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, blogging should be a way to express what’s on your mind, and not merely rhetoric or rhymes.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starting the year]]></title><description><![CDATA[Embarrassments and slip-ups aside, 2020 was a great year for revelations and growing up.
Like I said before, it’s about pushing the resting…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/starting-the-year/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/starting-the-year/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Embarrassments and slip-ups aside, 2020 was a great year for revelations and growing up.
Like I said before, it’s about pushing the resting state forward, even if we don’t get across the line. Let’s push further this year. 2021 does sound rad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not just about the actual work.
I should focus and put lots of time into design, ui/ux. Need to be robust. On the front-end side, it’s all about seeing the big picture, and now putting more time into understanding the architecture, the tools, the bootstrap; basically the scaffolding that’s holding everything together. It’s time to bend and expand the borders further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Diet&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gotta lose the flab. Gotta lose it all and start over. I made trials, so I know now what needs to be done. Then, once it’s all gone I need to start building the core. There’s no point eating and drinking sugar, I know it. Let’s turn it around. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Self Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a mission to be accomplished right. By summer, I’ve gotta be ready for what’s coming. I gotta pick English back up, and Spanish too while I’m at it. I can do it, I know and I’ve done it before. I’ve gotta keep my mind pumping fresh, so I gotta stay fit mentally, and in real. I got this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The autopilot dies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems laughably obvious now what’s really bringing me down, but we took an awfully long time to get here. But that doesn’t matter. Now we rise. Now we gotta stay on top of things. Now we gotta crave for excellence, put in lots of time pushing for perfection. It’s time to beat my par. And once you are hit with the confidence othing can stop you. You are gonna fly. The autopilot stops now.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[So, how did VISION 2020 fare?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Pretty abysmal, actually.
2020 was supposed to be perfect; it was at a respectable distance to call it the future, yet close enough to make…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/vision-2020/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/vision-2020/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Pretty abysmal, actually.
2020 was supposed to be perfect; it was at a respectable distance to call it the future, yet close enough to make plans for it.
It represented the future, because the number 2020 just sounds rad.
It also represented some normalcy, containing the numbers that also make up 20-20 vision.
And what comes next? 2025? That’s a round enough number.
So… Let’s make plans for that? It also aligns perfectly for a 5 year plan, and answers ‘where do you see yourself in 5 years?’ type questions.
Before taking such drastic steps, let’s look back at how our initiatives have worked out so far.
2020’s almost gone now; how have I fared? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;nnn&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 days of perfection. That’s all I could manage.
Also, I’ve realised that the nut problem is a consequence as much as a cause. The main problem is autopilot.
I got to get the withdrawal out of my system; otherwise I’m doomed, no doubt about it. I can’t yield; it just puts me back at you know what.
Gonna do an NND, next month. Let’s see if we can finally hold up strong to adversity and be a better person.
I got a point to prove. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Virtual distancing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This went hand in hand with nnn. I was rock solid the first 10 days-ish. I all went haywire after that.
It has been abysmal in the recent days.
I got to turn off twitter, comments sections, news of every kind, and focus of myself for a whole month.
I know I can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid-ish.
Again, I have these stretches of solid work, then I get lazy for a few days.
I got to have work as the foremost priority.
I got to hand off stuff faster, at the same time I got to innovate and plan rad things for the product we’re working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m impressed with what I could do.
Last week, I was gonna fold and not do the first assignment of the specialization cos I’m scared of coding. But I took the leap and I’m very happy with myself for finishing it.
I got to push because I’m sure this is just the start, and I’ll do much much greater things in AI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Side Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This didn’t take too much of a hit cos of autopilot, because I worked on passive stuff like design polish when on autopilot.
But I’ve got to streamline the pipeline processes, got to execute and be professional. It’s good that I’m exercising front end, design as well as managerial, architectural skills at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Self Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diet has been deplorable.
I got to have more workout sessions, eat properly for a month (no junk month?), play basketball, write more, polish my English and Spanish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Midnight walks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One spectacularly good thing has been that the amount and duration of midnight walks have been directly proportional to exponential development.
This is my workshop, this is my place of worship, reflection and meditation.
The basketball court is the sanctuary.
The walks weed out all extraneous thoughts and transport me to a different place.
I’m at my best, I think, I plan.
I got to make this a fundamental routine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoping that I have exciting stories for the next decade. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Colour Photo (2020) [Spoilers]]]></title><description><![CDATA[Aftertaste For some movies, the ending is a hard slap on the face.
You are not ready for what you are going to witness.
You are shell…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/colour-photo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/colour-photo/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Aftertaste&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some movies, the ending is a hard slap on the face.
You are not ready for what you are going to witness.
You are shell-shocked; you are hit by a truck, metaphorically.
You might not even process the implications of the ending the next few days or weeks.
Sometimes, you don’t even understand it and you move on.
But when you look back at the story, and if you do process it, boy you are in for a ride.
And in this case, it’s a world of hurt and despair.
There’s a lot of frustration and a feeling of injustice; blood seethes, eyes even well up as I keep thinking back to Colour Photo.
It’s just not right for what happens at the end of the movie.
I’m broken, and I wanna rage. It’s truly heart breaking.
A beautiful relationship, and a life with impending success and happiness are killed. Killed dispassionately.
And there is no happy ending. There is no optimism, except in the dishonest story the survivor chooses to tell strangers.
It has been two days, and I’ve only now begun processing that ending, and how brutal it was.
&lt;em&gt;This is what happens in the movie:&lt;/em&gt;
A very poor/hard working/principled/virtuous guy falls in love with a girl from his college, and the feeling is mutual; and for this, first his leg is permanently broken and he is left handicapped, he is fed his cattle, he is beaten up and threatened. He then proceeds to drink poison and die. His family does not even have a photo of him; so they remember him by hanging his shirt in their hut.
His best friend is beaten up/so traumatized that he turns insane for life, and he is admitted to a mental asylum.
I just can’t fathom this turn of events, and the impact of the movie lies in its aftertaste, not necessarily its runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ideas over execution&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I have always observed, and often appreciated in movies is having the heart at the right place,
and the central ideas even when most of the times they are not reflected in the actual movie.
Though Colour Photo was rather well done, especially the cinematography, it’s the core idea of the story that has left a scar in my mind.
Of course, the acting by Suhas and Chandini was impeccable, headlined by how she reacts when she sees his shirt hanging in the hut.
The teen comedy and some songs I could’ve lived without, but again, it’s the ideas that remain in your head after you finish watching the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The ending&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said before, I was not ready for that ending. I knew things did not turn out well, and there was tragedy looming,
I watched the fabricated ending unfold, and fell for it.
We are later shown what actually happens, in the same setting, and at the same time of day.
But instead of pulling off a heroic strat, the protagonist is bruised and beaten; he needs crutches to walk.
His life is done with; he knows it and talks about ending it all with his love.
They decide to consume poison at their hangout spot - the beach; they do,
but she is rescued just in time by her cousin while the poor guy lays there as his soul leaves his body,
helpless, and no one to check for him.
We see her in the present wailing over his shirt, and the movie cuts to ‘Directed by Sandeep’ rather non-chalantly, and the credits roll.
We are shown there is no help, and there is no guardian angel. There is no god or a force of good that causes miracles.
Tragedy ensues and life moves on. It can’t get more real and grim.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sparks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Status Update First, for the bad news. I have relapsed again. It was bad; I wasted a full day on addictions and autopilot.
I caved in and…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/sparks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/sparks/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Status Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, for the bad news. I have relapsed again. It was bad; I wasted a full day on addictions and autopilot.
I caved in and yielded to the withdrawal. I realised what was happening, and yet chose to let go of control.
I feel bad for that, and I think I’m better than that.
That being said, &lt;em&gt;the good news:&lt;/em&gt;
The past few days have been excellent! Not any normal good, but excellent!
I have been extremely productive, like never before, atleast the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;On top of things&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mind was racing, I was on top of things, and I had full control. No autopilot.
I resisted urges, I showed restraint, and I fought demons.
Looking back, it feels great that I was able to do that.
In fact, it gives me a kick thinking about that, and I cannot wait to do it all over again,
this time with a stronger punch. I was talking about trying to rekindle some of the fire I once had.
I think I did just that.
I got a load of things done, and not just that.
I wasn’t trying to do stuff to pass the days, but rather I was the maker of the plans,
and I was the executer. I had the big picture in mind, and I followed through with the actual work needed.
Work was great, learning was great, and I even started a little side project!
I think I can get addicted to being a strategist and an executioner; it’s sweet.
The past 3-4 days have given me immense hope and strength to do this right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Looking ahead&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sucks that I relapsed by day 5, but this has taught me so much!
This time, I’m gonna go against the dragon with knowledge of the past, and a lot more fortitude, and perseverance.
I cannot wait to kickstart this again, and be awesome at it.
I cannot stop thinking about success, and the future.
I cannot wait to persist, execute strats, innovate, excel and disrupt.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Torpor]]></title><description><![CDATA[Crappy autopilot How many years has it been now, that I have been in a state of torpor and lethargy?
My mind and body writhe, and this…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/torpor/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/torpor/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Crappy autopilot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many years has it been now, that I have been in a state of torpor and lethargy?
My mind and body writhe, and this entire pickle of a condition is honestly deplorable.
There has definitely been atrophy, more mental than physical. I thought my problems was relatively easy to solve, no they are not.
I’m barely scraping the surface everytime and calling it a day, but the core itself is broken.
This is what I do:
&lt;em&gt;It feels great to relax and not worry about anything. Problems will take care of themselves. The future will be fine. I just gotta exist. There. Ahhh. Feels great.&lt;/em&gt;
And then I wonder how the issues slap back at me.
I have developed a massive respect for people who are ripped or consistently fit. It takes a lot of effort and discipline to stay fit, the person’s fortitude manifests on their body.
Any change I try to take up, my mind now resists; it has so gotten used to nothingness, it opposes every new thing. What a pernicious way to live!
Plans are always made, goals mapped out, only to never be followed up.
Also sitting is baaad for me.
Especially during the lockdown, I sit lazy at home all day, and I’m bombarded with inane thoughts, or sometimes not even that. It’s like I’m on a crappy autopilot. Once I go for a walk after days of procrastination, my vision is unobscured, and I feel like I can make a dent.
A day of sitting and I’m back to square zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The case for discipline.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I feel like I should be kidnapped, kept under duress till I lose all my addictions and body fat.
Sometimes, I feel like I should join an army kinda program where I have no choice but behave.
But then, I’ve realised that it won’t solve the problem. What I’m missing is exactly what I want to avoid dealing with: discipline.
The restraint, and fortitude are exactly what I lack. That’s the core I talk about.
Also culpable is the lack of consequences; my parents have simply given up on me, or they have their own things to worry about, or they love me too much; this is no one else’s responsibility but mine. They always care for me, never blamed me for anything; I gotta make things right.
Another insidious factor is the lack of clear headedness to see what I’ve lost. I lost a career, a whole life on the other side of the globe, and I never think about it except during moments like this. Self preservation can do that, make you crave more of the ugly fruits, while turning your head away from the acres of fields you are burning down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;It’s a lifestyle thing.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not one single aspect, that needs to be fixed.
It’s not a one week thing.
It’s an entire way of life.
Oh my, what great things I can achieve if I actually put an appreciable effort into this.
I like to believe that I have a relatively gifted mind, and can do some things with ease. But again, I’m inclined to stay put and not put much mental effort for long periods of time or into future proofing.
I get many kicks, but the intentions don’t last. For example, I was watching a roadside vendor, and her kid sitting by the road, in their own world. That pulled some string inside me. How much can be done! I have everything I asked for, and I sulk in the corner for nothing.
Jeez. Serious problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The need for a game plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During moments like this, when I’m awoken, the big questions always haunt me.
What am I here for? What I can I do eventually?
I see all the potential and the possibilities ahead, and it brings chills every single time.
However, being passive all these years has also quashed and impeded my ability to think big, or envision about the grand future.
I can still sometimes imagine incredible things, and I hope periodic future think sessions can rekindle some of the fire I once had. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love,
Su&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Virtual Distancing]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s a lengthy post coming up about self help, but I’ve decided to document some ventures and experimentation. The bin is full. Lately, I…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/virtual-distancing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/virtual-distancing/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lengthy post coming up about self help, but I’ve decided to document some ventures and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The bin is full.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I feel like I’m being bombarded with news about anything and everything, and it has left an invisible, yet palpable load on the brain.
I think about 10 years ago when there was no bother except myself, things to do in a day, a week, a month etc, or just idle and laze around.
Now, the mind thinks about the big, but also all the poison, the acrimony, the hatred, scandals, controversy, and just about everything that’s irrelevant in the grand scheme of things.
Negativity, and  controversy are easy to observe and hard to forget. It’s like a car crash video you stumble upon; you fear and cringe, yet you are drawn to watch it, and you’re finally left with a bitter aftertaste.
It’s time to jettison some load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pointless awareness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s even the point of news, and when did it grow all pervasive? I don’t need to know what scandals happened, what conspiracies were uncovered, what new conversation was taken out of context, what phenomenon was being cancelled, what insignificant piece of information was the most important topic of discussion for a whole week before the next big thing supplanted it.
I don’t need all of this, I don’t need to stay on top of this. Most of it is static that doesn’t need mental effort, the exceptions being science, or tech, or any innovation that moves the world engine forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bliss&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My perfect state of bliss would be:
I wake up at a remote place, surrounded by trees and nature
I don’t pick up the phone to check news, but only to play some music, as I loiter around, or write in my journal
I introspect, retrospect and make plans for the future. I’m all alone, all my thoughts are uninterrupted, unfiltered and unfettered
I ride my bike over hills and curves, I stop for lakes or for food, then I ride some more
I think of ideas for products, apps, stories, screenplays, or plans of action
I theorize about life, space, consciousness,
I go for twilight walks.
I read books, lots of them.
I have food and go to bed to some podcast.
If it’s hardcore mode, I pledge to not interact with tech for a week or so, no phones no computers,  not even artificial lights, music being the only exception.
Just imagine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Baby steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best I can start off is through small steps that ease me into the zen way of life. The Sage way, the Saint ness. The zone, the flow state.
I need to begin right now, so I finally stop consuming and start living.
Let’s do this, right now.
No social media
No news
No reading comments!
Not even skimming though hackernews, for sometime.
Time to focus on work, and career endeavors.
Time to blog, vlog and document my state of mind,and reflect.
Time to get lost in thought, in the deep recess of my mind.
Let’s start back from Square Zero. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Transcendence]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s a flower at the top of the mountain
I fly and leap and sprint
Planes slide and shift
Reality oscillates playfully
Tantalizing my…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/transcendence/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/transcendence/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s a flower at the top of the mountain
I fly and leap and sprint
Planes slide and shift
Reality oscillates playfully
Tantalizing my spirit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I reach the clouds
And descend into the lavender fields
As the morning fog touches my skin
I’m ecstatic as I run through the greens
Sun rises and cools down
Moon is vanilla in taste and crisp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desert sands are dancing
Waves splash down on the rocks and turn into mist
Milky way lights up the sky
As comets dash across the zenith
The world is a box that fits in my palm
I shuffle it around and dance &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flashes of the past, and glimpses of the future
I’m everywhere at once
Permeating and fusing into.
Ethereal magic
Sparks of milk and drops of diamond
It’s rather white and pure
For a heart of darkness&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feelings]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s a spark, there’s a flame.
There’s a dream, there’s reality.
There’s what once was, there’s what’s now, there’s what could be.
There…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/feelings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/feelings/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s a spark, there’s a flame.
There’s a dream, there’s reality.
There’s what once was, there’s what’s now, there’s what could be.
There’s happiness, there’s joy springing from the heart.
There’s disappointment, there’s a reunion.
There’s ego, there’s vengeance, there’s sympathy.
There’s hope, there’s betrayal, there’s convergence.
There are qualms, there are doubts, there are moments of purity.
There’s a delusion, there’s expectation, there’s acceptance.
There’s hope, there’s an instinct, there’s destiny. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Twenty Five]]></title><description><![CDATA[Aspirations remain,
The bitter sweet past still keeps haunting,
Seems like I’ve begun living only in the past these days
Familiar smell and…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/twenty-five/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/twenty-five/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Aspirations remain,
The bitter sweet past still keeps haunting,
Seems like I’ve begun living only in the past these days
Familiar smell and sounds always transport me back a couple years. Was it really me? I was so lost back then; if only I had known better.
But the idea remains, I want to do something, I want to disrupt stuff. I still have the verve, maybe more than ever. I just lack the discipline to follow it through.
Maybe all in good time.
As Yuv said, you get closer every attempt, even if you fail. That is so profound; the key is to never stop and come at it stronger each turn. Kinda like that monster from Betrayal at house on the haunted hill.
Maybe I won’t cower the next time I’m faced with a challenge, and actually take it in the face instead of turning my back. I can see clearly in hindsight how easy all the things I learnt are, and how they appeared like mammoths when I step foot in. Just need to maintain the 20/20 experience.
Distraction is another key; monkey see, monkey no do.
Aghhhh how perspectives change in a matter of years.
This is my chance to push forward and not look back.
Feels great thinking about it.
Let’s disrupt. I like that word. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Upward Spiral]]></title><description><![CDATA[He unleashes wrath and torment
Destruction ensues his trail
He despises the witch who creates. Benevolent and brave
Her stride invokes awe…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/the-upward-spiral/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/the-upward-spiral/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;He unleashes wrath and torment
Destruction ensues his trail
He despises the witch who creates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benevolent and brave
Her stride invokes awe
As she fosters universes
Her kindness knows no bounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looks into the void of fringe
Waiting is a fool’s game
Purpose is lost forever
His time never comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She longs to make a new enclave
Her fingertips wave and
spew the essence
As she blesses another
With chance and love. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aimless and forlorn
He finds the goddess
concocting yet another world
Turns to her with fire in the
eyes and soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She melts his fury,
and burns the void
She consoles and he
confides in her the future.
Instance of eons in clarity
All that’s needed is infinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together they set out
Spreading life as we know
Minds collide and mingle
As they fly and sparkle
Hoping for something divine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worlds everywhere set ablaze
Teeming with hope and power
Knowing they will get their
time to prosper.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Homesick for a place far away]]></title><description><![CDATA[…before that, I had a perfect life in the US; I could wake up anytime, show up for classes, laze around, go shopping in the bus, play games…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/homesick/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/homesick/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;…before that, I had a perfect life in the US; I could wake up anytime, show up for classes, laze around, go shopping in the bus, play games, take long walks, rush to finish assignments, have amazing weekends, listen to great music, blog and chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are gone now, and it’s my fault. I feel really sick, and I just want life to go away, and take all the suffering with it. I miss something that I relinquished, and repent every second that I spent during the 2 years at Master’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really new to me; I was homesick during my Master’s too, but that was different. I had grown up my entire life at basically one single place, and for the first time in my life I was alone at the age of 22. I was living a completely alien life, and the entire world was new to me. It was hard at that time, but I dealt with it eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the feeling I have right now is inexplicable. I only stayed there for 2 years, I barely made friends, I barely went out, and I barely left home. But I miss a lot of things about that place. It’s because I had stashed away all my feelings when I was going through a phase, not finding work and dealing with news of my father’s ill health. But now it has come full circle to haunt me. The only way I can deal with this is by addressing it, and hopefully finding some inspiration along the way. Let’s make a list of things I miss about the US:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to music on the bus on my way to the University. The route 9 bus, the route 35, and the occasional route 12. The way the bus stopped and the voice prompt went off announcing the stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gator nights! Taking the empty bus in the night, going for bowling, checking out the events for the night, and having loads of fun, and oh, watching movies for free in the auditorium. Subliminally feeling that every girl is gonna check me out ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to Walmart for grocery shopping ever so often, making lists and completing them. Buying extravagant amounts of ice cream and chocolate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first failure of college life, and how I went for a walk listening to Stolen Dance, thinking I’m gonna turn it around the next semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually studying effing hard, scoring A- in Algorithms, hanging out with Yuv and prepping for the 3 exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The late nights walks with Yuvaraj! Can never forget those. I’m not a sucker for people, but that man has left an impression on me. I aspire to one day be as thoughtful, prudent, disciplined and tenacious as him. We would take breaks during study to go on walks in the chilly night. We would talk about everything under the sun. Till date, cold air reminds of those walks every single time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out of a slump in the final semester with Bharath, working our asses off trying to make sense of the assignment in Programming Language Principles, and finishing it, studying hard for the exams, and scoring A- in that as well. The daily visits to Library West, and then the Veterinary Library, getting a conf room together and working to finish the course, and subsequently prepare for jobs was a joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The period we were both homeless for a few days, living at (Newell Hall?) trying to not arouse suspicion. The grind to learn leetcode problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of not being successful, I have pleasant nostalgia thinking about Newell Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crazy trip to Louisiana, playing Dumb Charades with Aditya and Rishabh (my maaan), and the shenanigans there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching Yuv come back as a confident man, going to Everglades with the gang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I went out for drinks with the gang for New Year’s Eve, getting shitfaced, and lose all sense (love you Kanna).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time we went to a random Professor’s Thanksgiving party in a random’s car, seeing the other side of Gainesville for the first time in awe at the peaceful stretches of homes, having great food, spewing nonsense about randomness for my Thanksgiving speech, and a random man at the gathering telling me he liked my thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The times we would go out for movies together in the nights, walking through Butler plaza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being generally lost in awe at what life had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching plays at the University for the first time in my life (thrice), attending a tap dancing show, a weird art exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divergent thinking class! The only one I liked and couldn’t wait for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of it feels like a dream that I forgot everything about, and yet so palpable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Do I Want?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the far far future, I want to make a difference. I don’t wanna be a cog in the gears, but be a change maker, at the edge of innovation…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/what-do-i-want/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/what-do-i-want/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In the far far future, I want to make a difference. I don’t wanna be a cog in the gears, but be a change maker, at the edge of innovation. And I see my predilection towards Artificial Intelligence. Of course, it’s a broad field and I do not have a specific branch I want to get to, but in the best case I want to be contributing to technological singularity. A lot of presumptions need to be made in order to see that as a possibility, and more to place myself at the helm of that. But I want to try, and get in the scene to have a better understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another side of me that wants to earn well. I have chosen Front End Engineering, and it has been going well so far. I’m sure that as time goes by, I will make a good name for myself. So, what I wanna do is, work better and gain reputation and raises in the web development scene. I do enjoy the work, and being an aesthete I’m enthused about creating little utilities / good looking web applications. The visual artist in me is never gonna die, and working Front End inculcates and reinforces discipline and incisiveness; so there’s no major roadblocks I see down that path. And now, for the elephant in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Elephant in the room&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conquer my dreams and make them a reality, I need to overhaul my lifestyle. Of course, you are your habits; so I need to  tweak mine. But why should I think about what’s bringing me down, and process it, instead of blindly tackling the future? The connotation of the question makes it self-explanatory. It’s impossible to not address the foibles that plague progress and make it out of the low.
The issues have to be acknowledged so that they no longer lurk in the sub conscience mind, and you can consciously confront them everyday. It also clears up your mind. So, let’s address them now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Meet Lethargy and Friends&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have theorised that my physical lethargy has seeped into my mental state (the inner biology of the body manifests in the mental realm); I have always been introverted, diffident, and morose when I’m around people, and have always disliked change because it takes effort to adjust. In my everyday routine the same happens, and I’m more than happy to relinquish control and subject myself to passive consumption (youtube, gaming) where I don’t have to expend energy (physical and mental). Of course, this indulgence has costed me time, money and atrophy of mental power. Rebuilding good habits and maintaining a healthy lifestyle would definitely put me on the road to recovery.
Lethargy also results in indiscipline when there’s a deadline and you risk it, thinking it doesn’t matter.
You wake up late, show up late to work, procrastinate stuff and repeat the cycle.
The worst loss isn’t time, since you can always make up for it in the future. It’s the attrition of mental power. In that sense, lethargy is pernicious; not only killing good habits, but also making sure it’s hard to fight back. With all this being said, let’s plan for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Now, for the plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s necessary to sketch out a routine and stick to it. The thinking hat must not appear when the worker hat is on, since the thinking hat is susceptible to virus like lethargy and indulgence. The worker hat must blindly follow what the thinker hat said yesterday. This separation of concerns is necessary to make an impact. The thinker hat must not make decisions during times of primal urges. It must allot nominal periods for indulgences / primal needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ergo?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna utilise these couple days of personal time to make plans for the future. Routine, personality, personal development, career plan, Artificial Intelligence seem to be the contenders vying for a spot in the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the games begin!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A pledge for truth.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Alright, I’m going to embarrass myself again, but here we go.
I’ve successfully turned this blog into self-help material now (the self being…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/a-pledge-for-truth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/a-pledge-for-truth/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Alright, I’m going to embarrass myself again, but here we go.
I’ve successfully turned this blog into self-help material now (the self being me, not you, the reader).
But let’s keep doing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Note about self help&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to believe that it’s not worth motivating myself with these little articles because they’re never followed up correctly, but lately I’ve come to realise that what matters is the push, even if it doesn’t have a direct impact. Every article pushes me towards the goal, and it’s about gaining momentum the right direction till it overpowers the unwanted parts. The journey is about veering and correcting my boat the right direction with all kinds of tiny nudges and tugs, through the storm.
So, to know where to direct my boat, I need to ask questions.
And then try to answer them, and maybe come up with naive, idealistic plans that even though most probably fail, will still set me up in the zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why am I doing what I’m doing?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don’t know. I’m still recovering from a gigantic failure that my Master’s was, and found a low paying job. After starting to work, I lost the plot, partly due to the shift of focus towards my father’s health, but mostly due to incompetence. I like being carried by the currents, just drifting through the waves, and being caught up in the moment. Foresight has always been an issue for me, and I have recognised that. Right now, I am aware of my foibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where do I wanna be?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely not here.
The idea of finding out how we actually work, and the pursuit of mimicking that interests the fuck out of me. More specifically, the study of human brain / Artificial Intelligence.
However, I don’t know how this interest might translate into contributions even remotely useful in this endeavor. More importantly, I definitely do not have the tools / mental faculty to do that. However, I’m still young, and can definitely amount to something if the right decisions are taken at the right times.
And I definitely think it’s an idea worth pursuing in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;What do I gotta do?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I have to be at the command of controls, be fast af.
Mind’s gotta rush, run and pull.
I have wasted away a lot of time, but hey it’s never too late.
It’s time to aspire to be good at stuff, and not be content with mediocrity.
Realisation was the first step, and now I’ve got to make this state of mind a habit. And habit will take care of the niggles, and straighten me out.
Technically, I need to be leagues better at programming. And typing, for god’s sake. It’s been years since I learned how to type, and I still struggle. Coding should be a habit, a natural extension of how I think; it has to be an elegant, structured process of reading, thinking, brain storming, and coding (should be the easy part).
I’ve gotta pull myself out of the zone-outs every time they happen.
I gotta stay in the moment, when the action is happening, putting all my efforts into finishing the task at hand impeccably.
Gotta get out more often, take lots of breaks / walks. Staying in the same place breeds nothing but banality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s hoping for a bright time ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Deja Vu]]></title><description><![CDATA[I feel like I’ve lived this moment a thousand times before.
Exactly the same. The same scene in front of my eyes. The same music playing in…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/deja-vu/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/deja-vu/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve lived this moment a thousand times before.
Exactly the same. The same scene in front of my eyes. The same music playing in my head.
The ambience. The visceral feeling.
Like I’ve been ushered back in time to do something differently.
To observe what I didn’t before. Maybe change someone’s fate.
‘Come on, change the perspective. React differently. Think. Now…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before I get back to my senses,I see that I’ve lost it.
The fleeting Invincibility I felt is gone in a snap.
But the impact of the revelation hasn’t weathered away yet. I can still feel the adrenaline induced organs crying out loud in ecstasy. Begging me to act.
But my mind’s numb. Still in shock. I had one simple chance, and I ruined it.
Change the timeline, huh? More like a Sphere.
Deja vu,I guess.
Time loops repeatedly till you do what you’re destined to. Make the right choice.
Push forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Box of Issues]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have issues.
I have lots of them.
It’s high time I spit them out, or my brain will implode from this never ending cycle of rumination.
Let…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/box-of-issues/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/box-of-issues/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have issues.
I have lots of them.
It’s high time I spit them out, or my brain will implode from this never ending cycle of rumination.
Let’s unpack this mess, one issue at a time.
And before that, let’s try to brainstorm our way through why this will be the panacea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The monster lurks inside.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I’m an introvert, by definition. I like to spend most of the day thinking about what I want, what I’m doing, how things are going with me, and what I should do. However, I wouldn’t share what I felt with anyone till I started vlogging and now, I share my thoughts occasionally with the internet (myself).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I have been discovering about myself over the past few weeks is that I hoard feelings, issues and the state of my mind inside my head for long periods till they fade out, and try to go through the motions without confronting them head on.
It fires back spectacularly, and precious time (often days or even weeks) is wasted while I toil through office and home ignoring this giant elephant staring back at me.
Of course, this way of life has its own benefits, one being not spending too much time on companions (another article, hopefully) and a panoramic view of self (Is it really, though?), paving the way for prudent judgements / ideas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as it turns out, it’s not really worth the loss. I trap myself in loops, and I’m plain frustrated and confused most of the time. I want to do something, but I’m not sure what it is. I know I don’t lead the life I want, but I don’t know what to do about it. The feeling of helplessness and the pent up anger only take me sideways, missing the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let’s face them now. It’s now or never.
This is me, flawed and imperfect. This is me, bruised and hurt, from myself.
It’s time to face this reality, and strike a fear in the guy who lurks beneath my skin, hiding in the recess of my mind.
I’ve let this guy run my soul for a while, and it’s time to take control again.
Let’s talk about the fact of the matter, and work on defeating this monster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Materializing the Box&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve theorized that writing/recording what I’m feeling gives it a marker. The feeling is now a tangible object, with a shape, one that I can quarantine away, and choose not to look at or think about. It leaves my brain, and is trapped in this magic box that I create.
Problem solved!
My head is clear, and I can now face the future head on.
What’s left now is making plans and actuating them as a transparent process.
Let’s do this right, let’s do it now.
Whatever brings me down is going straight to the archives, and I will look at it in all its glory, analyzing me from the outside.
This is me you’re looking at; I have put myself out here, and I want you to look at me, in the most sordid form.
It honestly feels naked, but that’s exactly what I wanna do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why should I write?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Patterns Patterns are beautiful. They’re everywhere, they’re symmetric, and they’re persistent. Every few cycles, they manifest themselves…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/why-should-i-write/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/why-should-i-write/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Patterns&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patterns are beautiful. They’re everywhere, they’re symmetric, and they’re persistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every few cycles, they manifest themselves, and you know it’s time to write a ‘Why should I write?’ article again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ve screwed up your cycle, your career’s going nowhere, your hobbies are dead for good, and your creativity is waving at you from
Mars. You decide to take control, and start over again.
For real this time; no pretensions, no frivolity. Just pure motivation and caffeine rushing through your veins.
But the Gods are not kind to you, and the cursor is planted at its place firmer than your head on the pillows every morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, not this time. Let’s give it one more try, eh? If there’s anything even remotely noteworthy I’ve learnt through each cycle, it’s that impulse is that first crush from your high school whose name you don’t even remember, and tenacity is wifey material. She’s rich, she’s pretty, and she’s thoughtful. Marry her. Remember her name till you die, or you’ll go broke. Impulses won’t last, tenacity does. Duh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a fresh take on life (and addictions), let’s start over again. This will be the last time we start over again (hopefully not because I give up entirely the next time).
Let’s write. And before we write, let’s write about why we want to write.
So here goes…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Papers, please&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s all a blur when you’re in the zone, and you do things you won’t believe if you’re told about them the next day.
It’s all a blur when you’re &lt;em&gt;brain dead&lt;/em&gt; for years, and do things you won’t believe if you see traces of them later.
I badly want to be the first guy, and maybe I was, but my worn out brain won’t recollect what happened yesterday.
So, I need to document like the guy from Memento;
write, write a lot, sir. &lt;em&gt;Document that shit&lt;/em&gt;. Clip those thoughts. Everything has to go, so you can be awed over and over by your prowess to forget everything.
On a more serious note,
There have been times when I had made observations or had come up with invaluable philosophical guides, or mind-bending theories that I just can’t recollect now. My mind has numbed so much, and it’s really difficult to start over everytime it happens.
In conclusion, &lt;em&gt;document to not forget&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bring back the beast&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a beast 6 years ago. It was all happening. The beacons from outerspace or whatever the hell the aliens were doing was working, I was lit. Ideas just came to me, no probing required.
I was fast, and I was relentless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hungry 4 years ago, still had the magic needed for the witchcraft my mind needed to do.
&lt;em&gt;It’s all been downhill ever since&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be great if I could recollect the feeling of being there again, just to capture that spark, to reinstate that state of mind again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;No rush no fall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I’m still grappling with, with limited success.
&lt;em&gt;Rushing is for recruits in Siege&lt;/em&gt;, not quite applicable in the real world.
It’s important that you plan out whatever you intend to do in life; &lt;em&gt;haste yields waste&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;you rash, you crash&lt;/em&gt; are the general guidelines you need to live by.
Albeit being so important, I’ve overlooked this too many times, only to regret and reflect upon this.
More mistakes from here are only going to aggravate the damage, so let’s do this right, just this once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I’m not going anywhere anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Regrets]]></title><description><![CDATA[Forgotten pasts, forgotten times.
Sometimes it’s a tune, sometimes it’s a fragrance, sometimes it’s the cold rain.
Sometimes it’s someone…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/regrets/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/regrets/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Forgotten pasts, forgotten times.
Sometimes it’s a tune, sometimes it’s a fragrance, sometimes it’s the cold rain.
Sometimes it’s someone who has been there, and emerged victorious.
They bring a rush of guilt, a pinch of Nostalgia.
Sometimes happiness, a lot of times regret of what it could’ve been.
I try to ignore, but keeps hitting me over and
over till I acknowledge it.
Maybe asking me where I’ve been, what I’ve been doing.
Questioning why I abandoned it and absconded.
Maybe it wants me to get back there and finish what I started.
Maybe I need to forget all of this and bury it deep within my conscience.
Maybe I cowered and yielded at the wrong time.
Maybe I was too naive to see the reality, and face my demons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case, the phantom memories still incessantly haunt me, and I just can’t seem to get over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I can do, is write about it, hoping it alleviates some of the pain, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Recurrence]]></title><description><![CDATA[They work all day, they work all night.
They look at you, they send you thoughts.
They just want to see you think.
They want to know what…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/recurrence/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/recurrence/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;They work all day, they work all night.
They look at you, they send you thoughts.
They just want to see you think.
They want to know what goes on in that little brain of yours when the spark happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, we don’t know; but we do know that it’s important for them.
They work all the time relentlessly, not a mistake made because it’s simply not in their design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But every now and then, when the chief turns out of phase, an impish minion picks a memory from a run that already happened and feeds it back to you.
That crazy bugger just likes to watch you freak out.
He looks at your brain with awe, the way the alarms go haywire inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has he done!
He just likes to tip us off, and watch us remain helpless.
That little devil likes that fleeting anguish the barrage of cross firing neurons cause.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Enlightenment]]></title><description><![CDATA[A bad start, A good start. It all started with the American elections of 2016 December. I remember waking up one day, astounded. I had gone…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/enlightenment/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/enlightenment/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;A bad start, A good start.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started with the American elections of 2016 December. I remember waking up one day, astounded. I had gone to bed the previous night thinking how bonkers it would be if Trump won the elections.
How could this seemingly insane person win the freakin’ elections? This sparked my interest in American politics. Everyone in my circle had been bashing and ridiculing this guy for months.
I started out the traditional way, watching videos of ignorant Trump followers. It was fun while it lasted; witnessing horribly ignorant people making a fool of themselves on the internet. These people lacked common sense, and a general understanding of the world.
The curiosity gradually receded, and I got busy with other things.
Months later, I was back, now binging on liberal-bashing vids, which was a result of watching those SJW bashing vids, which was a result of watching those instant Karma vids, which was a result of watching those public outrage vids (I used to stay up real late at nights, with no purpose those days).
Ah, the liberals were making fools of themselves too! &lt;em&gt;Faith in humanity restored.&lt;/em&gt; These sjws were rebels without cause. Aren’t we all? They were fighting against oppression, injustice, bigotry, racism, sexism, chauvinism, and a litany of evils. But so carried away they were, that somewhere, they had lost their point and were sometimes fighting a lost cause, sometimes a non-existent cause. In a bunch of these videos, I saw this one man so effortlessly destroy people in debate. And he did it with charm and disdain. He had something about him. He wore a smile on his face all along, making sly, snarky, witty remarks at the opposition profusely. I also saw another man debating about transgender rights, and if its a valid gender at all, or it should just be considered as gender dysphoria. Just Google ‘Ben Shapiro The Boy scouts vid’. This person maintained a serious and an honest demeanor, but was very trenchant and snarky nonetheless. Both these people belonged to the right. They are Milo Yiannopoulos and Ben Shapiro respectively. Their style of communication and debate excited me, and pulled me to watch more videos of them just crushing their opponents. Also this guy, Steven crowder, is a good debater. Many of these Sjw and feminist bashing vids were very right wing inclined. The truth is, you can find videos of both the sides destroying the other side if you merely provide the search term. Now, this brings really disturbing effects. What happens is this traps us in a bubble of our own political ideologies by reinforcing our views. After all, the whole society is just make-believe. What these people believe is that winning an argument makes us right. &lt;em&gt;REKT. GOT HIM. NOPE.&lt;/em&gt; Just for the heck of it, watch a few videos holding the exact opposite ideology of your views. Gain some perspective. It’s an insidious world out there on the internet.
Stay informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Inspiration from an unexpected source&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mags shared a link on Youtube once. It was a couple of &lt;em&gt;Pranic healers&lt;/em&gt; on a NEWS channel claiming to cure illnesses through phone. They were speaking all sorts of gibberish and trying to make a living through chicanery. One person showed up 20 minutes into the news interview. His first line was “What is this nonsense?” The news anchor had been meek, but not this guy. This one wanted to prove a point. And he did. He proved LIVE on Television that these people were nothing more than quacks. The look on his face showed his contempt for this absurdity. More noteworthy was his insight into science and history, and his proficiency in English and Telugu as well. &lt;em&gt;This was BBG!&lt;/em&gt;Babu Gogineni, the cutie pie sent here to exterminate lies and delusions and bring 20-20 vision back in place for the society . I’ve since watched more than a hundred vids of this guy swooshing into news debates, tearing the ignorants apart with science and logic and conscience. His prey were &lt;em&gt;past-life therapists, astro psychologists, numerologists, celebrity astrologers, priests, pseudo scientists&lt;/em&gt;, and other proponents of flawed dogma. He one-handedly raised serious questions about the state our state, our country and the rest of the world is in. He was all about Rationalism.
All this binge-watching raised some &lt;em&gt;serious questions&lt;/em&gt;.
Is Religion the root of all problems? How deeply rooted was I in religion and blind faith and superstitions? How deeply rooted was my family?I’m an Atheist, but my belief was slowly being supplanted by false beliefs, just because literally everyone around me wasn’t even talking about this, and I was about to cave in to this ideology.I distinctly remember the Teachers’ day gaffe, where I called-up 2 of my close friends at midnight since the moon had a halo around, and my father had told me that it forshadowed humongous disasters. I was really embarrassed when nothing happened the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Analogy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how scary it is in North Korea. Kim Jong Un is THE God. People literally cry when they get to see him. Children are made to pray in his honor in schools everyday, when we know he’s not (I’d recommend that you watch the VICE documentary series on North Korea). It’s a saddening life that they lead, not knowing how the rest of the world is, horribly restricted by the law of the land, most of the country without electricity at night. How absurd it is, right?Wait, there’s already something like it in the rest of the world. It’s religion. And it’s institutionalized too! Don’t go out during an eclipse. You will have serious health problems this year. But, perform this simple pooja for a nominal amount, and I can make it void!
The problem with religion is, it’s been left unquestioned for far too long that people have taken it to be true.And questioning something that we’ve been brainwashed about all our lives, generation after generation, every single day, will just turn these people against us. The idea has been too deeply planted.We’ve been taught this since we were kids. Kids are stupid. They believe what we tell them. Tell them blue is orange, they will believe blue is orange. Tell them there is a world in outer space, with flying elephants and a world at the earth’s crest with demons with horns, &lt;em&gt;THEY WILL BELIEVE IT&lt;/em&gt;. That is the most critical time in a person’s growth, and these people are targeting the impressionable kids. Anyway, that’s a topic for another day.
Talking about Babu again, I like his approach to debate as well-Zero tolerance, zero fucks given to sweet talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final question, Is it enough to win the debate? And does majority mean correctness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Outbreak]]></title><description><![CDATA[What gets ‘em high? “We’re trying to shoot them down?” Su asked.
“That does nothing” the General scoffed.
He continued, “We need to blow ‘em…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/outbreak/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/outbreak/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;What gets ‘em high?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re trying to shoot them down?” Su asked.
“That does nothing” the General scoffed.
He continued, “We need to blow ‘em up. That’s our only shot.”
“And how do we do that” Su was thinking out loud.
“Bait and switch. We fill up the bunkers with their “fix”.”
“Coke? The F2 variant?” Su knew the plan.
“What else? Anyway, they go in, we close the doors, we blow ‘em up. Easy. Watch.”
Hordes of the infected charge into the bunker, grinning and howling. Not long before the entire bunker blows up.
“Alright, I’ve gotta do the same at camp Zero. Remember the training.” the General got on his chopper and it took off.
The pilot smirked at Su in a weird way before he got on the chopper.
“WAIT! THE PILOT’S INFECTED! HE’S GONNA KILL THE GENERAL!” Su shouted at the top of his voice, picked up an Rpg and shot the chopper down.
The General magically appeared beside him, and said “You stupid son of a”
“Nap time’s over. Wake up buddy” Bar said.
Su had been dreaming again. Dreaming of his training. Yet another dream horribly gone wrong ever since he aced the training.
“Hey. Wake up. We’re almost there.” Chan was waking up Nith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The mission&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Su, Bar, Chan and Nith were on a weapons salvage mission. The simplest one, albeit a tricky one, since they were embarking when
daylight was almost over. They were at their old dorm, to pick up a crate containing explosives. They didn’t have time during the
‘evacuation’, fighting off their friends who had just gotten infected. The whole dorm was a mess when they left, body parts flailing and blood squirting out of the bites their beloved friends left. They had no choice but to leave the weapons and all other supplies behind. Just send another crew on an errand mission to get it for them, right? Ironically, the command chose them to clean up their own mess.
“Quick getaway, alright? No messing around. Just waltz in there, collect the crate, sprint your ass back here. We’ll be out of here in a minute.” Bar was the driver, and in charge of the mission.
“Yea, mission detail was very clear. Pick up the crate, shake hands with our pals waiting for us, deliver their ‘present’ to you” Nith retorted. “I don’t like this place one bit.”
“Neither do we. Just make it quick.” Chan was the peace keeper of the crew.
Su and Nith reached the room that contained the explosives and began sifting through the mess to find usable ammunition. And there he was, Sam, sitting on his couch, right in front of Su, smoking one of the last cigars, grinning.&lt;br&gt;
“Whoa, whoa, who do we have here? Hey Sam, how’s it going?” Su remarked in surprise.
Sam, whose only last shred of consciousness was aiming at Su’s neck charged towards him in
excitement.
“Whoa, hold your horses boy. Down. Down.” Su quietly said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Infected&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the deal with the infected. They have a brain, and that’s pretty much it. It craves
for more of that sweet mix of heaven left in the world. When you’re being attacked by one, you can damage its body, but that does nothing; for their tenacity is plain stupid. They don’t care if they’re left limbless, or decapitated; the holy grail is holy enough to forgo any other physical pleasures.
Now, in combat situations, DO NOT SHOOT THEM. JUST DON’T. They’ll shout so loud your ears will bleed and their pals rush knowing there’s fresh blood. You gotta understand that they don’t want you.
They’re not vampires. They’re more idiotic than that. They just kill you to prove a point. To turn you
into one of them, so you can join their army in this fight for ‘justice’.
The best way to survive is to take those buggers down in a fist fight. The good ol’ way. Remember that they’re extremely weak until they’re provoked too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Su punched Sam right in the face, then jabbed him with a stick. Sam grabbed the stick, and Su kicked him at the calf, knocking him down.
“Pfffff” he yelled as he ran down the hallway.
Nith knocked down 3 of the infected, leaving them extremely confused as to how easily they lost the fight.
They got back in the car and sped off into the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Better is worse&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was already night when the group got close to the new dorm. There was a campfire beside one of the watch towers on the path. The man guarding it waved for them to stop.
Bar rolled down the window “What’s the matter? Emergency?”
“Umm..Yeah Kinda. Listen up, a convoy just passed me, almost everyone drunk.”
“Drunk? What are you saying?” Chan questioned.
“I know. So this is the news. Politician Rob’s son has passed away. This just broke out. You people look well educated, you know he was the main proponent of the experiment that went horribly wrong and caused this mess.”
“So they were out celebrating. Umm what’s the concern?” Nith asked.
“You guys know what happened the last time people were out ‘celebrating’.” the man replied.
“Aight. We got the message. Thanks. And stay safe.” Bar knew what was going to happen.
Su banged his head against the dashboard, and gasped. “I don’t wanna change dorms again.”
Bar calmed him down, and pointed to the front. They had reached the dorm’s gate. But it was barely recognizable, sprawling with cheerful people crowding the road, screaming and laughing. Some were going out, some were going in, but all of them had booze in their hands, and were clearly drunk.
“Aight, I think we all need to worry now. A replay of last year.” Bar mumbled.
“Jesus. Fuck! We need to evacuate. Get your things and let’s rendezvous in 10 minutes. Go go go!” Chan said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Su reached his floor, and it was in complete chaos and disarray.
“Hey, Rob’s son has died!”
“That son of a bitch is deaaad!”
“Oh yeahhh!”
“Time for drinks!”
“Hey Su, come on, where are you going? Join us, let’s get drunk and play cards, huh?”
Su ignored everyone and rushed to his room. Mags was in there, and he seemed to be in a rush as well.
“Yo, heard the news?” Su asked.
“Yeah, Rob’s son is dead, right? Hahahaha. The infected got him. But hey, look man, I think I need to get some of the stuff, man.” Mags seemed anxious.
“Cocaaaiinaa?”Su asked, knowing the answer.
“Yeah, man. The F2 variant. I know you’ve stashed it somewhere here. Please man, I wanna relax.” Mags groaned.
“But why the F2? Dude, that’s a protected resource. I can’t give that. Besides, I donno where I’ve stashed it.” Su was uncomfortable.
Mash got up and started searching the room without Su’s consent.
“Dude! Where is it? Aaaahh! Where is it, where is it, where is it?” Mags was getting cranky.
Su knew something was wrong. He saw outside his room that Mags’ shoes were dirty. He had been outside. God knew what happened. Su was almost done packing his stuff.
Outside the dorm, somwhere Downtown, some people saw the death as an opportunity to start a riot. They took to the streets, breaking the windows of stores, plundering and hooting and getting drunk.
Maybe, just maybe they were making too much of a sound. Maybe, one of them had some ‘Cocaaiina’ in their backpack. Maybe that gave off a scent a tad too strong, a tad too long.Maybe it looked like an invitation for the infected. Maybe these people weren’t prepared for an attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the dorm, Su was now done packing, and he set out to the door, and asked Mags to tag along.
Mags was now acting hysterical, and denied to come with him, and demanded that Su give him some of that goodness.
Su noticed a scar on Mags’ neck when he turned around.
Su, now scared, said “Hey, you’re my brother. But if you don’t wanna come with me, it’s fine. I’m going, bye.”
Mags now growled like a dog; his face had gotten slightly disfigured; he quietly bolted the door and advanced towards Su.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[DUTY]]></title><description><![CDATA[Somewhere in a snowy part of the world K was listless. All his pals were fatigued. The squad was still wading through
the snow on foot with…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/duty/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/duty/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Somewhere in a snowy part of the world&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K was listless. All his pals were fatigued. The squad was still wading through
the snow on foot with their commander aboard the ATV, and the rest of the patrol followed suit.
Sun was just about to rise, so that was a relief. The chilly blizzard was eventually going to subside.
“Ten more minutes to civilization!” one of the soldiers yelled.
“Aight let’s stay frosty” replied K.
“Pun?” asked his pal.
“That’s all I got now.” K retorted with disdain.
This was a simple infiltration mission, no hostiles expected on their way; the only enemy was the blizzard and the snow.
The squad still had to remain stealthy, orders from the commander. Their vision was extremely limited, thanks to the weather.
“I see houses” K shouted.
“Dang it, we couldn’t see shit till we’re 20 feet away?” said J.
“Good lord, where is everyone? There’s no people and all the doors are unlocked!” exclaimed P.
“Bingo! Let’s use the houses to move, get in, get out through the back doors. We’ll have cover, and we’ll have heat.” K directed.
“No, brother. We need to get there ASAP. No time to dally. Bear the cold for a few more minutes, would ya? We’re almost there” ordered his commander.
“Makes sense” said K. “Aight people, straight ahead. Let’s keep going.”
As they made their way into the town for about 20 minutes, the blizzard got worse. Echo Squad was left blind as bats.
U saw something. “Wait a minute, Halt! Take cover! Y and F are dead! They’ve been shot. Looks like a sniper! Watch out.”
The squad quickly took cover, and as they proceeded to move with caution, 3 others were shot in the head.
“Holy cow! What’s happening?” P was scared.
2 more of them got shot  right infront of them.
“We’ve got to keep going as fast as possible. Run, so we don’t give them the time to aim. Run!” the Commander shouted at the top of his voice.
K knew something was sketchy about this.
“They’re using a drone to spot us. Heat signatures.” K whispered to P.
“Doesn’t make sense. It’s our airspace.” P answered.
“I know. Listen, follow me.” K insisted as he cut through to the side with P. They made their way around, running as quietly as possible. They eventually entered an abandoned robot manufacturing plant, and continued to run to the other side.
“Holy molly, get down NOW! 12 O’ clock!” P said in a frantic tone.
They spotted 2 enemy snipers camping on the first floor.
“There’s definitely more of them. I hear radio chatter. They’re spread out all over the area.” P whispered.
“There’s no way our patrol can make it through. We’ve gotta take them all out.” K infered.
P continued, “Affirmative. These 2 first. On my mark. 3…2… ”
Before they took the shot, the snipers got their heads blown out from the side. All P and K could hear were more suppressed rifles going off further to their right.
“Not our squad. What the fuck is going on?” K exclaimed.
One of the snipers got lucky, and retaliated. The gunshots were now loud and clear. K and P took cover and just listened with panic. There was a big shoot out for a while, and then the sounds stopped.
As K and P got up the ladder to take a look, detonators set off simulatenously, making a huge noise, and mangling the bodies.
“Our guests wanted to make sure everyone’s dead. I believe they’ve left.”
K and P took snipers from a corpse and looked for them. They could see an ATV speed away at a distance.
It then stopped briefly, and their commander got into it, and then it vanished into the snow.
After a few minutes of deliberation, K realized what was happening.
“They’re making it seem like a war has been started.”
“What do you mean? We’re already in war” P was confused.
“It has just aggravated. Now this will be a whole different war. &lt;b&gt;We’ve started a bigger one.&lt;/b&gt;
And someone’s gonna use this to keep all the eyes away from something else, something much bigger than this.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Square Zero]]></title><description><![CDATA[Looks like I’m doing this. Our mind is a constant source of new ideas and thoughts, which often end up garbled after we move on with time…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/squarezero/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/squarezero/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Looks like I’m doing this.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mind is a constant source of new ideas and thoughts, which often end up garbled after we move on with time, and new
ideas and thoughts supersede these pieces of brilliance we once had.
Bookkeeping is essential to record one’s state of mind, and for retrospection. I remember the times when my mind was
bustling with fantastic theories, that I couldn’t keep track of them after a while. Most of them have become obscure with time;
I have forgotten all the specifics and the minute details. That is when I started blogging, to try and keep track of them
as well as to share these with people who might be fascinated by the same things as I am, which has also introduced me to
some amazing people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Voice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking of the interest in sharing things, I have developed a new interest in developing a strong voice over a lot of topics,
and sharing them. Voice is absolutely necessary for any person over anything. That’s how people develop perspective, and that’s
how they build character. However, just developing a voice could be detrimental, if it’s not shared and debated and questioned.
Sharing this voice out in the open with confidantes, or friends, or the public leads to debate and discussions and arguments, often fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Under the rug&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I badly need to take time off consuming content and put it to good use analyzing and creating. The past few months have
been a true eye opener for me, and I was exposed to an array of critical topics like politics, human psychology, the big picture,
superstitions, and decisive observations on a lot of things that happen behind the scenes. This will be a place where I can analyze
what I’ve consumed, and develop a perspective. The interest has also extended to influence others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This is good, right?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything else is a delusion, this is atleast a good way to spend time. This will also aid me in refining my vocab and communication style. I’ve always wanted to learn and master critical writing, and writing in general. And lastly, this will also make me tinker more with github and Jekyll and NodeJs and a plethora of the other options out there on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Box of chocolates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is going to be awesome! I’m gonna write fiction, non-fiction, some songs maybe, and what not. Just that I’ll take more time
developing and refining the articles, to make it a notch better than &lt;a href=&quot;http://tlojarus.blogspot.in/&quot;&gt;TLOj&lt;/a&gt;.
Here’s to a bright future filled with hope and better conscience!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Zone]]></title><description><![CDATA[O’Great power, what do I do?
I get so overwhelmed, I don’t know what to do
There are thoughts that set my mind ablaze
All the things I could…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/zone/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/zone/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;O’Great power, what do I do?
I get so overwhelmed, I don’t know what to do
There are thoughts that set my mind ablaze
All the things I could achieve
But none too simple to undertake
I long to fly far away and purely meditate
Grasping the truth; as simple as it is
I long to indulge in the purest tones of debauchery
Seeking and devouring, till the carnality cloys
But O’ Great power, how can I spare time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’ Great power, I get caught up
I’m lost in the whims,
How can I fly when
The trappings of life have me grounded
And the constructs get me trapped
I’m a fool, for I fall for them everytime
I feel like it’s all coming together
Just before my vision falls apart
And my little mind loses sanity
O’ Great power, do I always turn to you and pray?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’ Great power, life has left me jaded
How do I disregard the noise
The banality of it all gets me nauseated
How do I thwart the reality that encompasses
Maybe I just need to concentrate enough
And wait for the eventual epiphany
That O’ Great power, I do know how
To get through the tough times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get in the zone, I can see the blank
Reality has faded and made way for the ineffable
I feel weightless, like the light itself
Time dilutes and my vision sharpens,
My senses ditch the universe and probe inside me
I feel nothing but my thoughts
When I witness my unbridled power
My state of mind and its course clear as water
O’ Great power, what have you done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you infiltrated my soul?
Or were you always present?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The giant fucking deal !]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s make a fucking deal.A giant fucking deal.
Ten years from now,I’m gonna own a fucking huge home.Like a really biiiig one.The house that…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/giant-fucking-deal/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/giant-fucking-deal/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let’s make a fucking deal.A giant fucking deal.
Ten years from now,I’m gonna own a fucking huge home.Like a really biiiig one.The house that everyone else’s gonna envy,desire.The one that makes people fucking jealous.The one that’s the ultimate house that one can ever dream of.The home,which looks and feels plush,makes people go nuts.
A house made of and having really fucking amazing things.Made of the best things ever used to make a house.A house with jaw-dropping aesthetic appeal,surreal interiors.The one that feels so spacious and luxurious that you’ll think you’re in a fucking seven star hotel.
Okay,then.The deal’s sealed.Note the date,it’s
The Twenty Fifth of July , 2014.  That is, 25-07-2014.
By The Twenty Fifth of July,2024 ,that is 25-07-2024, the deal will be fucking fulfilled.
How it’s gonna look :
It’ll at least be a four storey building.
The outdoors :
In the space before the house,a big porch,and then lawn.
On the side,a swing and space to just walk around,or sit and talk.
On the back,space for a badass garage,with a fucking amazing car.
And a super fast bike too.
There’ll be two entrances side by side,one enough to fit a four wheeler,and the other enough to fit a person.
For the walk-in entrance , a frame made of some materials will be surrounding them,and a carpet on the surface.The lawn will be on the left,and the four wheeler entrance on the right.This walk-in entrance will lead to the porch.The compound and the porch will be lit by super luxurious lamps.Even the walls will be lit by lamps from the inside.
The indoor views :
The fourth and the top most floor will be mine.
It’ll have a big and bad ass living room.
A huge TV,home theater,gaming console and all and sickly soft sofas to sit.
The ground floor will be for the guests  and will also serve as the common living room.The first floor’ll be for my parents.The second one for relatives, or guests who crash at our house.
The first,second and third will have huge balconies.The third floor will also serve as a gorgeous party floor,preferably with a pool too.
All right,i’ll start prepping for this vision of mine to come true.
Let’s fucking go !&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bioinformatics Classes]]></title><description><![CDATA[She asks an intelligent question ‘Why won’t it work with your method?’
They’re stumped. No clue in the world. They stand there, dumbstruck…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/bioinformatics-classes/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/bioinformatics-classes/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;She asks an intelligent question ‘Why won’t it work with your method?’
They’re stumped. No clue in the world. They stand there, dumbstruck, like deers caught in headlights. Her smug face is swelling with pride. She has just posed an unanswerable question. No one saw this coming. Oh no, they weren’t. Touche, miss. You got us. You got us cold. And we were thinking we were the gods, cleverly thinking we had everything under control, pretending to be listening to the presenters while watching football on our laptops and scribbling lyrics from a Black Keys song. The whole world has come crashing down on us. Some guy in one of the front benches is amused, and looks at the rest of the class, if some genius can crack her clever riddle. Fucking sycophant. Or he’s genuinely awed at her wits. I remain stoic and nonchalant, trying to prevent this hot mess from seeping through my skin. What a tragedy. No one answers her question, and she doesn’t either, leaving us blind. Same shit, different day. I look at my phone and notice that all this drama’s nearing it’s end, and rush through the rest of the lyrics. Not a bad job. No. Very bad. But it’ll do. They wrap up their talk, and I thank heavens.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Love]]></title><description><![CDATA[‘Am I weird?’ she asks.
‘Of course not.’ I reply.
‘You’re lying.’ she quickly reads my mind.
We get up from the table after finishing dinner…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/love/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/love/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;‘Am I weird?’ she asks.
‘Of course not.’ I reply.
‘You’re lying.’ she quickly reads my mind.
We get up from the table after finishing dinner, and walk out of the restaurant. Her every step is quirky; sometimes she takes long strides, sometimes jumps in the air as she walks, sometimes makes dramatic pauses and resumes. Her gaze is into the milkyway itself, her mind wanders a thousand places in a second. The constant music in my ears from all her singing douses me with melody, and her constant questions rekindle my wisdom.
‘Am I weird?’ she asks again.
‘No honey, you’re not.’ I reply.
‘You’re lying.’ She catches me again.
One moment, she’s out capturing the stars with her camera from the wild forest, next moment she starts playing the guitar sitting on the porch. One day, she plans to be the best painter in the world, next day she starts studying the human dna.
As we walk down the deserted streets at midnight with the moon peeking through the clouds, she stops walking, looks up at the stars, then looks at me, and asks
‘Am I weird?’
I take a long pause, turn to her, hold her face as I whisper ‘Yes you are. You are the weirdest person I have ever met. Weirder than me.’
She gets visibly shocked, and tries to say something, but I interrupt her ‘Honey, that’s what drives me mad to you. I can’t stop thinking about you. I can’t stop hearing your songs, I can’t stop looking at you. Your quirks. Your eyes. Your mind. Your thoughts. I can’t live a day without you, without listening to your plans, your ideas, your questions. You’re not afraid to listen to your instinct, and that’s what I love about you. If the name for that is weirdness, then yes, you’re weird. But that’s what makes us human. That’s what makes us alive. Yes, you’re weird.’
I stop speaking and we just stare into each other’s eyes for a long long time. And then, we start smiling and continue walking.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spy Game - Dawn]]></title><description><![CDATA[But the front looks kinda bland. Where’s that striking edge dude? Get those curves sharper.’
‘It’s not bland…umm…yeah kinda. The back is…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/spy-game-dawn/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/spy-game-dawn/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;But the front looks kinda bland. Where’s that striking edge dude? Get those curves sharper.’
‘It’s not bland…umm…yeah kinda. The back is sexy though.’
‘Totally.’
‘And why do you draw over curves so many times? It’s there, alright! It looks messy when there’s too many of them.’
‘Agree on that.’
‘Yeah… I tend to do that when I’m thinking and don’t know how to proceed’
‘You gotta stop that. You got grilled nicely by Shyam sir when he saw your diary.’
‘Hoohoohoo yeah that was crazy. He was actually shocked to see so many lines drawn over and over.’
‘And the cars! His expression was priceless when he saw your car doodles all over the books.’
‘Stop it guys! He loved it.’
‘Yeah, right! Me loves it, he said’
“Hahahah”
The three boys were inconspicuously ‘hanging out’ at the last bench, their usual spot. The desk was riddled with doodles of cars, logos, names and future plans. That was their home, their place of worship, their place of motivation, demotivation, sleep, distraction and concentration all at the same time; the floor covered with broken bits of square shaped flour sweets, tamarind Hajmola, candy wrappers and lollipop sticks; it was the place where they dreamt of the bright future where they were the medal winners for excellence in academics and vision for the future. Their talks ranged from roast of teachers, current crushes, local cinema, cricket and celebrities to underrated indie films, tech visionaries, science in movies, ideas for a successful military coup and state of the mind to dreams, LED covered color-changing transparent cars, theories about the universe and plans for technological singularity. But mostly how to make car doodles better and sharper.
S was the executioner, being the guy drawing the doodles.
X was the visionary, being the pessimist brat dismissing every single sketch that came out of S’s mind.
M was the accountant, keeping track of the time they wasted every single class. And sometimes making sensible and sharp comments on the doodles. Everything was perfectly fine the way it was till one fine day, an incident planted something deep in their minds that it changed their lives, taking S and M on a twisted path with X leading them on a parallel road to oblivion. That one day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M and X were busy critiquing S’s newest piece of art, on a cold afternoon in Mr. Murthy’s class. Murthy was dozing as usual, on his chair. Some students were talking trash, some were talking about girls in the next classroom, these guys were creating their masterpieces, but most of them were actually studying.
‘Mocking aside, how does it look, be honest.’
‘Ummm..meh. They’re all starting to look the same now’ M said.
‘All trying to blend in with the system.’ X was lost in thought.
‘Yo whatchu lookin’ at?’ M and S looked at X.
X pointed to everyone in the class, one by one ‘Look at these guys, they don’t know what they’re doing, or why they’re doing it. Just trying to blend in.’
‘Maybe they really love this subject’ S replied.
‘Huh, that’s funny. Ask them and they’ll tell you otherwise.’
‘They’re scared that if their grades drop, they’ll be part of the army’ M said.
‘Then why is our state called a democracy? What’s the point?’ X was angry.
‘The point is, we gotta become something in lives to change this’ S tried to reason.
‘But by the time you become something, you’re old, and you lose interest.’
‘And the older people don’t bother because of all the perks.’ M said.
‘Oh, the perks! The free house! The car, the funds, the booze. What a strategy. We’ve gotta give it to our ruler. He’s a genius.’ S was smiling.
‘And they force their little ones to do the same. The younger ones are kept on a leash, and the older ones become part of the cult.’ M was seeing the pattern clearer than ever.
‘But we can’t say it’s wrong, right? Whatever he’s doing, our country is getting better every day. Now we’re one of the most developed nations of the world!’ S argued.
X quickly retorted ‘But what’s the point? What’s the point of doing this? Of being zombies? Of studying? Of living like this? What do we get out of it? We’re not free! There’s no room for creativity. For artistic expression, for reason, for debate, for criticism. Why even exist?’
‘Yeah, we’re too constrained’ M agreed.
‘Exactly!’
Murthy woke up hearing X’s loud voice, and he was furious. This was not the first time this happened. Students were simply not supposed to talk during classes! How could they disobey the teachers?
‘You sons o…Get out of here!’ Murthy got out of his chair and charged towards the last bench.
‘Sir, we weren’t talking.’
‘It wasn’t us.’
‘Get up!’
As they got up, Murthy whacked their backs once before pushing them out of the class.
‘I said get out of the class. You guys are useless. Worthless pieces of crap.’
‘Sir’
‘But…’
Before they could muster courage to speak up, he slammed the door shut on their faces. With the fear still receding, the three guys leaned against the wall outside the class and sat on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘That fucking Murthy!’ X was livid.
‘Why do we always get thrown out of the class?’ M was depressed.
‘That fucking Murthy.’
‘Yo chill. This was for the better. It’s break time for GSL in 10 minutes. My baiibee! will come out !’ S was happy.
GSL was the adjoining class, called Girls Super League, who studied medicine. The guys from the rest of the classes would die for any chance to get a glance at them.
‘I knew we were lucky!’ S was blushing.
‘To get thrown out? Screw you. That fucking Murthy!’ X retorted.
‘Hey girls, the sexxxxy guy is here. Get a good look before he goes back in’ M was already adjusting his hair.
‘Thaaat fuckking Moorthy! Why aren’t we allowed to discuss while we’re studying? Who the heck doesn’t get doubts while learning something?’ X was analyzing what had just transpired.
‘But we weren’t studying right?’
‘We were discussing the things that matter!’
‘How the hell would he know what we were doing? The issue is, he didn’t ask us what we were doing! Right away slammed us!’ S stepped in to X’s support.
‘This is exactly why we need to take on this system! We’re pushed into this shithole and we’re expected to study for 12 hours without any break? What are we? Robots? And teachers like this guy, they deserve very bad things. Don’t push us past the tipping point! You’ve just done that! You fuckers! You are gonna pay the price! All of you! Fuck the system! Fuck it! Let’s do our plan. Let’s freaking come at them till they can’t take it anymore! We need to bring a revolution. A change. That’ll permanently change this thing.We don’t want order! Order kills creativity. Order fucks with our mind. Brings fear into our minds. We don’t live anymore. We just pretend to blend in the herd. I can’t do this anymore. Fffffuck this! Let’s go with our plan.’
‘Yeah! We can’t do this anymore! Right, M?’
‘Hell yeah! Let’s do this.’
As the bell rang, girls came out from GSL one by one, giggling and laughing, looking at the trio sitting outside the class, yet again.
M waved at everyone and they waved back. S was just smiling, and as soon as his lady came out, turned his head down in a flash.
‘What the fuck are you afraid of? Look at her, goddamnit!’ X was happily angry. ‘Hey S, our S likes you!’
She looked back, gave a shy smile and walked away giggling.
‘Ooh, yeah baby! She likes you.’ M was happy. ‘Me loves you. Me loves you long time!’
‘Shut up, dude!’ S was blushing.
They got up and as they walked over to the food stalls with the crowd, X whispered
“Our lives have changed, my friends.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lightning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Game As incessant rains lashed out on the village, the game reached the final round.
Tensions soared, concentration peaked and minds were…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/lightning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/lightning/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Game&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As incessant rains lashed out on the village, the game reached the final round.
Tensions soared, concentration peaked and minds were doing a zillion calculations every second.
All the roads were over a feet deep in water, and one could find the reflections of the midnight moon in the waters.
Neither the loud rains nor the abrupt thunders could tamper with their game. They were in the zone. Playing the game. Phase locked.
And after what seemed to be a very short time,the game ended. Jay finally won.
‘Woo Hoo !’
‘Not again.’ said Su.
‘Don’t do your neigh. Please.’ said Prady.
‘Yee Haa !’
‘There we go.’ said Goutham.
‘So you get your money back.’ said Su.
‘Yes, I do! ’ exclaimed Jay.
‘Alright, let’s take a break.’
‘Yeah, let’s take some pictures of the view.’
‘Great. But don’t make a bokeh again. It sucks.’
‘I like ‘em. So buzz off.’
‘Bzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz’.
‘Peace. Won’t argue with you.’
They made their way out of the room on the top floor of the mansion to the patio, Su started clicking pictures,
and Jay and Prad started smoking.
Hills encompassed the village on all sides, and lightning struck them repeatedly. The sky was eerily dark, and the moon was now nowhere to be seen.
‘This is odd’ remarked Goutham.
The lightning wasn’t ordinary. There was too much of it, and the guys knew something wasn’t right.
Through the rain, on the other side of the village, they spotted something.
There was one little area on a hill where lightning struck almost periodically,
and after four or five cycles, about ten adjacent places up there would get hit by a wide line of almost blinding light.
Though they initially dismissed the idea, curiosity got the better of them, and they soon started making plans to get there.
‘Okay, how?’
‘The panther’ Prady said.
‘Really, bruh?’
‘We’ll get drenched to death.’
‘Oh come on. The panther will always be our official adventure vehicle we all agreed.’
The panther was an old topless 4x4 Jeep they had bought together. Rain couldn’t stop their insane quest for adventure.
‘Panther it is, then. Let’s roll!’
‘WE’RE GONNA DIE!’ Jay hollered.
‘HAHAHAHA’
They got in the panther, with their usual outfits: overcoats, hats, torchlights, backpacks and unrivalled bravado.
The panther easily made its way through the water into the jungle. They had already gotten drenched, but that wasn’t the priority on their minds.
It was the mysterious appearance of this supposed lightning.
As the panther waded through the huge rocks and the dense trees and the puddles of water, they realised that they were so alone in the darkness.
Only the sounds of the vicious rain hitting the rocks could be heard, apart from the scary thuds from the thunders, and the continuous splashes of water off the panther’s tires.
Slowly ascending the hill, they looked back at the village which lied at the chief depression of the hills. Apart from that, there wasn’t any light, and darkness dominated the world.
The strikes on the peak ahead got stronger and louder.
The panther couldn’t take them any farther as the forest grew denser. But the relentless crew got down and made their way to the destination, staying close to each other.
The wind grew stronger, and the rain drifted along its direction.
‘This would make a perfect setup for a movie.’ Su was excited.
‘Would it be tragic at the end too?’ Prad joked.
‘Stop it guys, you’re scaring me!’ said Goutham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Peak&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as they reached the peak, the biggest group of strikes hit close to them, and the shock carried by the impact grounded them.
As they gathered themselves up, what they saw baffled them. The lights in the village were gone. Hell, they couldn’t even make out if the village was still there.
The sky was now more like outerspace, completely dark,only seen when lightning appeared.
The rain had stopped, only god knew when. The ground beneath was already drying up, too freaking fast for them to believe.
As they still recovered from the shock, the most unexpected thing happened.
Out of the blue, something lit up in the sky, and whooshed past the hills, making a shrill, unbearable sound.
The light wasn’t white. It was blue.
They thought it was a comet, but this thing flew so freaking close to the hills. And what was that sound? Like an old lady’s whine.
What in the world just happened?
Whatever it was, and whatever just happened, they knew life wouldn’t be the same again. Their hearts began to race, and as shock receded, adrenaline took over.
They looked at each other in unison.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Great Destroyer]]></title><description><![CDATA[He was staring into absolute darkness.Nothing else, just plain void. There was no sound, no smell, no sight, no sense of  touch either. He…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/the-great-destroyer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/the-great-destroyer/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;He was staring into absolute darkness.Nothing else, just plain void. There was no sound, no smell, no sight, no sense of  touch either. He felt weightless, spaceless. But behind him was something he didn’t want to see. He knew he had finally reached his ‘destiny’. And he was scared to see what the creator looked like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He finally mustered the courage to turn. He turned.He turned, and experienced the ineffable. Before him was a figure, glowing in the dark.He realised this was outer space, and the figure stood on a one dimensional platform. Stood? No. It was moving violently, shaking all its parts. Now he could make out the shape. It resembled a human form. But gosh, it was atleast a million times bigger than him, and he could see the eyes too. The eyes were flaming red, lava pouring out from them. Its glow blinded him.Its hair flew all over the universe. And the whole universe started shaking with its moves, resonating with his steps. Was he dancing ? What was happening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accompanying the dance was noise he couldn’t bear. The sounds were absolutely disjoint glitches of varying kinds, too loud and shrill that he started bleeding and screaming. But he caught the rhythm soon and suddenly, they all appeared to be in perfect sync. The sound was surreal, the perfect embodiment of art. It was music.It was music at its purest form. He couldn’t believe what was happening. Since he knew he was in his mind, was it a virus? That was what pathogens looked like?
No. Was it a sub-atomic particle? Was it God ? Was it god? Was it god? It was god? That was god !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly he was transported with all kinds of emotions.He was scared and overwhelmed,he was laughing and crying,he was calm and angry and ecstatic; and joined the figure which continued to dance with fury, joy and vigor while the god music continued to blare. The music reached its crescendo now.He felt weightless, he felt invincible dancing and jumping like that.Tears stormed down from his eyes. He knew what he wanted to do. He wanted to ‘surrender’ himself to god. He wanted to die.Merge with god.Become a part of him. Is this what the vedas talked about? He was a rational person, but he couldn’t believe what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All his senses now worked in unison and gave him the unified sense. The one only attainable by god. He grew in space, and time. He was turning into god. He could see the space, the earth, its people, the zillion other planets thriving with life, which appeared so close to earth. He could see the beginning, he could see the end. He could see the beings, calling out to him. He could see the infinite and the infinitesimal. All through his mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The social network]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was crashing there for a little bit while i was taking care of somethings,but she’s done for the summer,so she’s back at her parents…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/the-social-network/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/the-social-network/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was crashing there for a little bit while i was taking care of somethings,but she’s done for the summer,so she’s back at her parents’ place.
The homeless rockstar of Palo Alto!
All right!
What’s your plan for this summer?
(Mark stares at the strippers)
Mark?
Yea,i was looking at the architecture.
I asked what your plan for this summer is.
A hundred schools by the end of this summer.
We’re gonna go to the restroom.
All right!
Your date looks so familiar to me.
She looks familiar to a lot of people.
What do you mean?
A Stanford MBA named Roy Raymond wanted to buy his wife some lingerie.But he was to shy to shop for it in a department store.Comes up with an idea for a high end place that doesn’t make you feel like a pervert.
So he balls a forty thousand dollar bank loan,balls another forty thousand from his in-laws,opens a store,calls it “Victoria’s Secret”.Makes half a million dollars his first year.Starts a catalog,opens three more stores,and sells the company to Leslie Wexner and the limited for four million dollars.Happy ending,right?Except few years later,the company’s worth Five Hundred million dollars,and Roy Raymond,jumps off the Golden Gate bridge…Poor guy,just wanted to buy his wife a pair of thigh-highs,you know?
Was that a parable?
My date’s a Victoria’s secret model,that’s why she looks familiar to you.
Wow.
Don’t be impressed.I saw your blog.
Ah,that was for web cretins.
You know why i founded Napster?
No.
The girl i loved in high school was with the co-captain of the Varsity Lacrosse team,and i wanted to take her from him.That’s why i decided to come up with the next big thing.
Wow.
Napster wasn’t a failure,it changed the music industry for better and for always.It may not have been a good business,but it pissed a lot of people off.Isn’t that what your Facemash was about?They’re scared of me,pal and they’re gonna be scared of you.What the VC’s want is to say “Good idea,kid!The grown-ups will take it from here”.But not this time!This is our time!This time,you’re gonna a business card that says “I’m CEO,bitch!“.That’s what i want for you.So where the hell’s Eduardo?
He’s in New York.
Sucking up to ad execs.
He’s got an internship.
The company’s here.A billion dollar company’s here.Eduardo wants to be a businessman,and for all i know,he’s going to be a good one,but he shouldn’t be in New York,kissing Madison Avenue’s ass.This is a one in a lifetime ‘HolyShit!’ idea !And the water under the Golden Gate bridge is freezing cold.Look at my eyes and tell me i don’t know what i’m talking about.
Do you still think about that girl?
What girl?
The girl from the high school,with the Lacrosse thing,
No!
If you guys are gonna talk about gambling,we need shots!
So a hundred schools by the end of this summer,right?
Yes.
Gesture of good faith,while you’re getting to a hundred schools,i’m gonna put you on two continents.
Wow.
If you need a place to crash,i think you should definitely come and live with us.
Let’s line up some shots!
Excuse me.you can take this away and bring back the 1942.
Absolutely,Mr. Parker.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Me and my school]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my personal memoir on “Me and my school”. I still distinctly remember the first day of my seventh class.That was the first day after…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/me-and-my-school/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/me-and-my-school/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my personal memoir on “Me and my school”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still distinctly remember the first day of my seventh class.That was the first day after i changed schools.I had joined Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan.All i had heard about the school was that it was the quintessential school with all the good things.So naturally,my expectations were incredibly high.I was really nervous and honestly.a bit scared too.My former school had made English speaking a mandatory task.So i thought that would be the case with this school as well.I entered the campus about half an hour early and was awe struck by the sheer size of the campus.The school had really huge play grounds and huge corridors as well.So i sat in the class early and was preparing for the first class according to the time table.A while later,a student entered the class room,noticed me and sat by my side.He was very warm and took me through the entire ‘how things work’ stuff at school.The first thing that struck me was that he wasn’t speaking English.And then,when other students entered the class room ,he just started swearing at the others for no reason at all,and the other guys reciprocated as well.I was literally terrified as i was so naive back then.So,that is how my time in my school began.I definitely felt that it was an absolute mismatch.I was among the toppers of the class in every exam and all i did was study.That was how it was done till my sixth,in my old school,where we were pressurized a lot to gain good marks.I was so shy and hesitant even to talk to girls!
But here,things were really different.My peers didn’t seem to worry too much about marks or the exams itself.I was initially dismissive of them,thinking that they were not going to prosper well in life.That being said,i have already said that i was naive.Then,things gradually began to change.Some events from school still remain fresh in my mind and probably will be for the rest of my life.Like,me crying in the class and complaining to the teacher that a guy hit me with a ruler.The mysterious person who left really horrible letters in my name and hid them in the assignment books that were being submitted to the teacher.The pyschopaths and bullies who were constantly involved in feuds and washroom brawls.Times when i sprained or fractured my arms more than twice a year.The time i first met my best friend for life.The time i had my first crush.By then,i had completed my eighth class.I had cried through most of the events.I had many revelations and started gaining maturity.
By ninth, i was part of a cult in the class.According to me,that was one of the best times of my life.The time of self-discovery.I started rationalising and questioned everything.Religion,god,customs.Everything.Things began to make sense.I had started playing sports and games and had become active,thanks to my best friend and the cult.I had a reputation and made a name for myself in the school.But still,something was not right.I still felt a little mismatched in my school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenth class is when the students of other schools were busy preparing for the end exams right from the start and schools had hectic schedules.But not our school.Everything was normal.Calm.Peaceful.The same old way.That’s when i started realizing the importance of good schooling.Our school had the best faculty ever and state of the art infrastructure.We had classes in art,music,dance.electrical gadgets,games and sports,events,functions,guest lectures and many more.I began to feel that i was at the right place after all.You had absolute control over yourself.Nothing was being imposed.Nobody was being forced.Then,i reluctantly became the ‘Head Boy’ of the school,having no idea about my role.Then came Teachers’ Day,where the students were supposed to be the teachers for one day and teach the younger students.Obviously,i had to be the principal.And,everything went horribly wrong that day.Nothing went according to the plan and it was a disaster.In such a situation,my older self would have wept and felt bad about it for a long time.But i had changed.Now i took the matter in a lighter way and we all laughed it off.I took the positives from the event and planned better for the future.And i was not the topper in my board exams,and i did not care.I still had a braggable grade,and i felt content with what i scored.I had become more sociable,active and mature in many aspects.
My schooling days taught me numerous things which made me what i am today,etching countless memories which will never fade.
Peace out.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Movie Mania]]></title><description><![CDATA[At last,i’ve made a movie.A real one.A movie that lasts 3 minutes.Tis called Counter Strike.The story is not any of those i mentioned in the…]]></description><link>https://squarezero.github.io/movie-mania/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://squarezero.github.io/movie-mania/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;At last,i’ve made a movie.A real one.A movie that lasts 3 minutes.Tis called Counter Strike.The story is not any of those i mentioned in the previous posts.It’s a short thriller-comedy movie.I think it came out well enough.
The story’s simple enough:
Two guys get bored in a class with no professor,and come out of the class to roam.They later return to the corridor with imaginary guns,mimicking soldiers and their movements.After they reach the class room,one of them rushes in,and points the gun at the class,in a “Hand’s up!” kinda style.He later realises that something is wrong by the actions of the students,and turns back,only to find the professor behind him.The other guy feels that something is wrong,so rushes into the classroom,and flourishes the imaginary gun at the classmates.The professor strikes him with a chalk and the guy finally realises that he’d been ambushed.We then see both the dudes being forced out of the room.While walking out,both of them get an idea.They take out imaginary grenades out of their bags,and after counting down to 3,throw it into the class room and run away merrily.
This was supposed to be shown in a hilarious manner.I think i’ve been able to make it the way i imagined it.
See, the most important thing for me is the music.Music’s the soul of the movie.I got the idea for this movie when i was playing the song “I’m a man” by Black Strobes.
Okay,now i’ve got more plans,more of basic ideas rather than fully developed scripts.
The first one’s about a dream that a person has,and how the same dream occurs to another person of interest.Another one’s about showing an incident in different perspectives,and the prologue and epilogue for each perspective.This would be a thriller.
Now,the big show!
I’ll definitely develop this one into a movie.The concept is intriguing.
It’s about three(there’s actually a fourth) psychopath buddies,and how intelligent they are in executing their actions.The basic idea is to show how a person would react if suddenly someone tries to attack them,and swears at them and gets ready to beat them up for no reason that they know of.
I’m thinking of the title “Happy birthday!” and also “Prank the pranksters after the pranksters prank you” or just the shorter form : “Pr da pr af ta da pr pr yu”.
It’d also be a thriller.I’m thinking of a more serious tone for this one.
I’m also thinking of a first person perspective for the fourth prankster until the end,and reveal his face at the end,where he’d play a bigger prank.I’ll think more about this blog after i make this one into a movie mostly.Or maybe earlier!Who the fuck knows? Cheers .&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>